Visual Materials from the Records of the National Woman's Party
Prints & Photographs Division, Library of Congress
Visual Materials from the Records of the National Woman's Party 1884-ca. 1965 bulk 1920-1960
Guide Record
ca. 450 items
Prints & Photographs Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
These photographs are primarily portraits of persons involved in the National Woman's Party.
For information about Prints and Photographs Division collections and services, see the Prints & Photographs Division's Reading Room Home Page.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Organizations
National Woman's Party, collector.; National Woman's Party--1880-1970.
Subjects
Women's suffrage--1880-1970.; Women--Civil rights--1920-1970.; Women--Organizations--1920-1970.; Women--Political activity--1920-1970.
Form/Genre
Group portraits--1880-1970.; Negatives--1920-1970.; Photographic prints--1880-1970.; Photomechanical prints--1880-1940.; Portrait photographs--1880-1970.; Postcards--1880-1970.; Printing plates--1920-1970.; Proofs--1920-1970.; Protest posters--1910-1940.; Slides--1880-1970.; Tintypes--1880-1930.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transfer; Manuscript Division (Records of the National Woman's Party); 1986 (DLC/PP-1986:212)
Additional form available
Digitized images of some items in the collection and their associated identifying information are available through the Prints & Photographs Online Catalog, by searching using the call number (or title), "[input call number or title]"
Scope and Content Note
Includes primarily portraits of National Woman's Party (NWP) officers, suffragists, politicians and business women; NWP meetings and formal gatherings; women delegates at United Nations sessions on human and civil rights; views of the organization's headquarters at Washington, D.C.; postcards depicting women's suffrage slogans; anti-war posters from the National Council for Prevention of War, the American Friends Service Committee, and the Women's International League.
Organization of the Collection
Organized by subject and by format into the following filing series which serve as call number designations: LOT 13445 (photographs and prints); POS U.S. (Posters); Supplementary Archives (Printing plates); LC-MISC (negatives and transparencies).
http://lccn.loc.gov/2001696350
Container List
- People and activities of the National Woman's Party 1884-ca. 1965, LOT 13445
  Includes primarily portraits of National Woman's Party (NWP) officers; suffragists; and other women in politics and business; NWP meetings and formal gatherings, including Susan B. Anthony celebrations; the NWP Detroit Convention of 1940; women delegates at United Nations sessions dealing with women's rights issues. Also includes the organization's headquarters in Washington, D.C. (Sewall-Belmont House); views of suffragist Alva Belmont's home at Port Washington, Long Island; a few photographs of NWP founder, Alice Paul's home in Vermont. Also postcards depicting women's suffrage slogans, a 1913 suffrage parade in Washington, D.C., and President Wilson's inauguration and parade at Washington, D.C.
  Organized roughly by subject.
- Printing plates
  Four printing plates are in the Supplementary Archives (Suppl. Archiv.) filing series. Two depict a woman on a horse and the slogan "forward into light"; a third reproduces the "jailhouse door" commemorative pin designed by Alice Paul in 1917; the fourth is a half-tone plate depicting a portrait of an unidentified woman.
- Posters ca. 1910-ca. 1940
  - World peace. Before another Christmas still less of armanent and none of war, [1918?]; POS U.S. R618, no. 1 (B size); Rochon-Hoover, artist; 1 print (poster): color; 49 x 32 cm.
  - The whole earth is everychild's home. No matter where his home is, the whole earth today is everychild's treasure chest and workshop and playroom, [193-]; POS U.S. R618, no. 2 (C size); Rochon-Hoover, artist; 1 print (poster): color; 45 x 30 cm.
  - Labor fights wars and then pays for them. Organize for peace., [193-]; U.S. N372, no, 2 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 78 x 53 cm.
  - Disputes will continue to arise between nations. Do you want them settled by reason or poison gas? By a world court or world war?, [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 3 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 63 x 47 cm.
  - General pact for the renunciation of war..., 1929; U.S. N372, no. 4 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster): color; 110 x 68 cm.
  - U.S. presidents for 30 years have favored a world court! Write your 2 senators. We must join now., 1931; U.S. N372, no. 5 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 55 x 41 cm.
  - Remove a cause of war. Provide access for all nations to the world's resources and markets. Will you pay this price for peace?, [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 6 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; American Friends Service Committee, funder/sponsor; Women's International League, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 55 x 41 cm.
  - Law not war, [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 7 (C size); Rochon Hoover, artist; National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 61 x 46 cm.
  - Betraying humanity! Private trading in armaments knows no frontier, no patriotism, no humantiy. The government must prevent it., [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 8 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; American Friends Service Committee, funder/sponsor; Women's International League, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 55 x 42 cm.
  - The world must choose at the world disarmament conference, [193-]; U.S. N 372, no. 9 (C size); Talburt, Harold M., 1895-1966, artist (attributed); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 56 x 44 cm.
  - The sermon on the mount. Poverty or peace? Armaments or bread? World disarmament conference, [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 10 (C size); Talburt, Harold M., 1895-1966, artist (attributed); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 56 x 44 cm.
  - Machine massacre. War the world's enemy. Support disarmament conference., [193-]; U.S. N372, no. 11 (C size); National Council for Prevention of War, funder/sponsor; 1 print (poster); 56 x 38 cm.